<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="rubys@us.ibm.com">Sam Ruby</author>
    <title>Gump</title>
  </properties>

<body>

  <section name="Recurring build problems">
    <p>These represent "known problems".  In some cases, they represent a
    temporary problem that will be synched up at the point of the next
    release, in other cases they represent an abject failure to communicate</p>

    <subsection name="commons-latka">
      <p>Latka depends on function which was subsequently rolled back from
      httpclient.  Latka development continues with a snapshot of a jar which
      does not correspond to any release of latka or the current cvs head.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="dbxml">
      <p>The Xalan team is in the process of changing an API that dbxml uses.
      The reason for the change is to support DTM, however the change is
      apparently not being made in a backwards compatbile manner.</p>
    </subsection>

<!--
    <subsection name="tyrex">
      <p>Tyrex will compile cleanly with Ant 1.3 and log4j 1.0.4.  It also have
      every indication that it would compile (albeit with deprecation warnings)
      and work with the latest release of log4j (1.1.3).</p>
      <p>Most of the errors are due to a Ant bug fix made during the development
      of the 1.4 release.  the Tyrex source tree contains files which will not
      compile, but are to be excluded from the build.  The excludes attribute
      is coded as excludes="tyrex/corba/*", but this really should be
      excludes="tyrex/corba/**" as the files to be excluded are contained in
      subdirectories</p>
      <p>The remaining errors are due to usages of interfaces which were
      deprecated in various releases of log4j and now have been removed.</p>
      <p>Three attempts have been made to contact the tyrex development team.
      On the third attempt, I received a response that these problems are
      temporary.</p>
    </subsection>
-->

    <subsection name="scarab">
      <p>For a while, scarab was trying to keep up with the evolution of
      the torque component of turbine-3.  Eventually, this became too disruptive
      and work has continued using a snapshot of turbine.  This snapshot does
      not correspond to any public release or the current HEAD.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="xml-fop">
      <p>Batik is in the process of correcting what they have described as
      a fairly fundamental design error.  This should only affect a small
      minority of batik users.  Unfortunately, xml-fop is one of the users
      affects.</p>
      <p>At the present time, there is a good line of communication between
      the two projects, and the fop team understands and agrees to this change.
       They plan to step up once the changes are released.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section name="Other Issues">
    <p>These represent versioning issues that will not show up in any
    gump run, but you may need to be aware.</p>

    <subsection name="jakarta-avalon">
      <p>Despite the relatively recent release of Ant, most Avalon projects
      will not build with that version of Ant.  They require a small but
      important change in the jar task.  Of course, they build with the version
      of Ant checked into their respective cvs's, but the question is: do we
      really want or need a separate version of Ant for every component?</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-tomcat-4.0">
      <p>Tomcat4 integration with tyrex depends on interfaces which tyrex
      removed over six months ago.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-turbine">
      <p>Based on inspection, I don't believe that turbine-2 and turbine-3 can
      coexist in a classpath.  The jakarta-jetspeed, jakarta-turbine-jyve, and
      jakarta-turbine-orgami projects depend on turbine-2.  The
      jakarta-turbine-flux and scarab projects depend on turbine-3.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section name="Recent success stories">
    <p>TBD</p>
  </section>

</body>
</document>

