<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="rubys@us.ibm.com">Sam Ruby</author>
    <title>Gump</title>
  </properties>

<body>

  <section name="Recurring build problems">
    <p>These represent "known problems".  In some cases, they represent a
    temporary problem that will be synched up at the point of the next
    release, in other cases they may represent an abject failure to
    communicate.</p>

    <subsection name="commons-latka">
      <p>Latka depends on function which was subsequently rolled back from
      httpclient.  Latka development continues with a snapshot of a jar which
      does not correspond to any release of latka or the current cvs head.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="dbxml">
      <p>The Xalan team is in the process of changing an API that dbxml uses.
      The reason for the change is to support DTM, however the change is
      apparently not being made in a backwards compatbile manner.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section name="Other Issues">
    <p>These represent versioning issues that will not show up in any
    gump run, but you may need to be aware.</p>

    <subsection name="jakarta-avalon">
      <p>Despite the relatively recent release of Ant, most Avalon projects
      will not build with that version of Ant.  They require a small but
      important change in the jar task.  Of course, they build with the version
      of Ant checked into their respective cvs's, but the question is: do we
      really want or need a separate version of Ant for every component?</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-tomcat-4.0">
      <p>Tomcat4 integration with tyrex depends on interfaces which tyrex
      removed over six months ago.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-turbine">
      <p>Based on inspection, I don't believe that turbine-2 and turbine-3 can
      coexist in a classpath.  The jakarta-jetspeed, jakarta-turbine-jyve, and
      jakarta-turbine-orgami projects depend on turbine-2.  The
      jakarta-turbine-flux project depends on turbine-3.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section name="Recent success stories">
    <p>This section describes cross project compatibility issues which were:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>detected by gump</li>
      <li>the changes would likely have otherwise gone undetected until
      release</li>
      <li>involved changes to one or both products</li>
      <li>the changes were done prior to release.</li>
    </ul>

    <subsection name="jakarta-log4j">
      <p>September 2001: in order to more closely resemble the JSR 47 API,
      the Level class replaced the Priority class, and the Logger class
      replaced the Category class.  This was originally done in a manner which
      was thought to be backwards compatible, but there was subtle reasons why
      this was not the case.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

</body>
</document>
