<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="rubys@us.ibm.com">Sam Ruby</author>
    <title>Gump</title>
  </properties>

<body>

  <section name="Recurring build problems">
    <p>These represent "known problems".  In some cases, they represent a
    temporary problem that will be synched up at the point of the next
    release, in other cases they may represent an abject failure to
    communicate.</p>

    <subsection name="jakarta-avalon-cornerstone">
      <p>The default target appears to attempt to build tests that don't
      exist.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="tyrex">
      <p>Tyrex has customer requirements to be compatible on log4j 1.0.4.  The 
      current log4j release is 1.1.3 and it introduced a number of APIs, and 
      deprecated a number in the process.  Release 1.2 is in its second alpha 
      release and has removed some of the APIs that Tyrex continues to use.
      A <a href="http://tyrex.exolab.org/list-archive-dev/msg00223.html">
      patch</a> using reflection was provided but not yet integrated.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="xml-fop">
      <p>Batik is in the process of correcting what they have described as
      a fairly fundamental design error.  This should only affect a small
      minority of batik users.  Unfortunately, xml-fop is one of the users
      affected.</p>
      <p>At the present time, there is a good line of communication between
      the two projects, and the fop team understands and agrees to this change.
      They have already resynched twice, and will try to track to the
      release.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section name="Other Issues">
    <p>These represent versioning issues that will not show up in any
    gump run, but you may need to be aware.</p>

    <subsection name="jakarta-tomcat-4.0">
      <p>Tomcat4 integration with tyrex depends on interfaces which tyrex
      removed over six months ago.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-turbine">
      <p>Based on inspection, I don't believe that turbine-2 and turbine-3 can
      coexist in a classpath.  The jakarta-jetspeed, jakarta-turbine-jyve, and
      jakarta-turbine-orgami projects depend on turbine-2.  The
      jakarta-turbine-flux project depends on turbine-3.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-velocity">
      <p>The combination of Texen, Ant 1.4 or later, and placing jars on your
      classpath can result in unexpected behavior.  This has been isolated
      to a standalone 
      <a href="http://marc.theaimsgroup.com/?l=ant-dev&amp;m=100264908721443&amp;w=2">test case</a> 
      and being investigated by the Ant development team.  Meanwhile, an 
      undocumented attribute, reverseloader, which when set to the value "true"
      on taskdefs which defines texen may help.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section name="Recent success stories">
    <p>This section describes cross project compatibility issues which were:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>detected by gump</li>
      <li>the changes would likely have otherwise gone undetected until
      release</li>
      <li>involved changes to one or both products</li>
      <li>the changes were done prior to release.</li>
    </ul>

    <subsection name="dbxml">
      <p>October 2001: The Xalan team is in the process of changing an 
      undocumented API that dbxml used.  The dbxml team determined that the
      reason that they were using that undocumented API no longer applies.
      This was corrected after the second beta of dbXML - meaning that the
      users of their next release will be able to upgrade smoothly to
      Xalan 2.2 once it is released.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="jakarta-log4j">
      <p>September 2001: in order to more closely resemble the JSR 47 API,
      the Level class replaced the Priority class, and the Logger class
      replaced the Category class.  This was originally done in a manner which
      was thought to be backwards compatible, but there was subtle reasons why
      this was not the case.</p>
    </subsection>
  </section>

</body>
</document>
