<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="rubys@us.ibm.com">Sam Ruby</author>
    <title>Gump</title>
  </properties>

<body>

  <section name="Workspace">
    <p>This represents the combination of projects (either referenced 
    directly or indirectly, via profiles) that are to be built together.
    By default, workspaces are named after the hostname of the computer
    which you are building on.</p>

    <table>
      <tr>
        <th>Attribute</th>
        <th>Description</th>
        <th>Required?</th>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>Basedir</td>
        <td>Fully qualified directory into which all projects will be
          extracted built.
        </td>
        <td>No</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>pkgdir</td>
        <td>Default directory in which to find projects which are installed
          as packages instead of being built.  Examples being various jars
          which can be downloaded from Sun's web site.
        </td>
        <td>No</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>cvsdir</td>
        <td>Workarea for cvs extracts.  The generated update script will
          do the cvs checkouts or updates into this directory.  The generated
          build script will copy the results into the basedir prior to 
          building.
        </td>
        <td>No.  Defaults to ${basedir}/cvs</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>logdir</td>
        <td>Directory into which the generated html logs are placed.</td>
        <td>No.  Defaults to ${basedir}/log</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td>version</td>
        <td>Which version of the Gump dtd this workspace was defined against.
          The current version is "0.3".
        </td>
        <td>Yes</td>
      </tr>
    </table>
    <p/>

    <subsection name="property">
      <p>Global properties which are to be applied to every Ant execution.
      Commonly used to specify the "build.sysclasspath" property which
      tells Ant how to deal with classpaths specified inside the build.xml
      files</p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>Attribute</th>
          <th>Description</th>
          <th>Required?</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Name</td>
          <td>Name of the property to set.</td>
          <td>Yes</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Value</td>
          <td>Desired value</td>
          <td>Yes</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="profile">
      <p>Collections of projects and repositories.  While a complete
      profile can be defined here, typically one is referenced via
      href.  For a complete description, see the documentation for
      <a href="profile.html">profile</a>.</p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>Attribute</th>
          <th>Description</th>
          <th>Required?</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>href</td>
          <td>URI of the file containing the profile definition</td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="module">
      <p>An individual module to be included.  While a complete
      module can be defined here, typically one is referenced via
      href.  For a complete description, see the documentation for
      <a href="module.html">module</a>.</p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>Attribute</th>
          <th>Description</th>
          <th>Required?</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>href</td>
          <td>URI of the file containing the module definition</td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="project">
      <p>An individual project to be included.  While a complete
      project can be defined here, typically one is referenced via
      href.  For a complete description, see the documentation for
      <a href="project.html">project</a>.</p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>Attribute</th>
          <th>Description</th>
          <th>Required?</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>href</td>
          <td>URI of the file containing the project definition</td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>home</td>
          <td>Convenient way to specify an override for a root/home 
            element.
          </td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </subsection>

    <subsection name="repository">
      <p>An repository from which one or more modules may be obtained
      While a complete repository can be defined here, typically one is 
      referenced via href.  For a complete description, see the documentation 
      for <a href="repository.html">repository</a>.</p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <th>Attribute</th>
          <th>Description</th>
          <th>Required?</th>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>href</td>
          <td>URI of the file containing the repository definition</td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>method</td>
          <td>Convenient way to specify an override for a root/method 
            element
          </td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>user</td>
          <td>Convenient way to specify an override for a root/user 
            element
          </td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>path</td>
          <td>Convenient way to specify an override for a root/path 
            element
          </td>
          <td>No.</td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </subsection>

  </section>
</body>
</document>

