<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!--
 Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
  contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
  this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
  The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
  (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
  the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>

  <header>
    
    <title>Apache Gump&#x2122;</title>
  <authors><person name="Sam Ruby" email="rubys@us.ibm.com"/></authors></header>

<body>

  <section><title>Recurring build problems</title>
    <p>These represent "known problems".  In some cases, they represent a
    temporary problem that will be synched up at the point of the next
    release, in other cases they may represent an abject failure to
    communicate.</p>

  </section>

  <section><title>Other Issues</title>
    <p>These represent versioning issues that will not show up in any
    Apache Gump run, but you may need to be aware.</p>

  </section>

  <section><title>Recent success stories</title>
    <p>This section describes cross project compatibility issues which were:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>detected by Gump</li>
      <li>the changes would likely have otherwise gone undetected until
      release</li>
      <li>involved changes to one or both products</li>
      <li>the changes were done prior to release.</li>
    </ul>

    <section><title>dbxml</title>
      <p>October 2001: The Xalan team is in the process of changing an 
      undocumented API that dbXML used.  The dbXML team determined that the
      reason that they were using that undocumented API no longer applies.
      This was corrected after the second beta of dbXML - meaning that the
      users of their next release will be able to upgrade smoothly to
      Xalan 2.2 once it is released.</p>
    </section>

    <section><title>jakarta-log4j</title>
      <p>September 2001: in order to more closely resemble the JSR 47 API,
      the Level class replaced the Priority class, and the Logger class
      replaced the Category class.  This was originally done in a manner which
      was thought to be backwards compatible, but there was subtle reasons why
      this was not the case.</p>
    </section>

    <section><title>jakarta-ant</title>
      <p>December 2001: a manifest task was added to Ant which collided with
      the manifest task contained within xml-fop.  What followed was the most
      impressive cooperation between projects I have ever witnessed.  The fop
      project removed their manifest task, and the Ant project changed their
      code so that the manifest task that fop previous had would have
      overridden the one provided with Ant.</p>
    </section>
  </section>

</body>
</document>
